* [Activities](javascript:void(0))

    Predict and earn Loyalty Points!

    New content from creators you follow

    Discussions and Community Insights

    Showcase of User Uploaded Images

    Ranking of our most popular creators

    Discover the latest community reviews

    Read latest updates in flight simulation

    Contribute and collect badges
    
* [Add-Ons](javascript:void(0))

    View the full list of add-ons

    A comprehensive list of new uploads

    Trending add-ons of the day

    Most popular updates of the day

    Most recent updated add-ons

    Today's most downloaded add-ons
    
* [Liveries](javascript:void(0))

    Explore the full spectrum of available liveries

    Discover the latest additions to our library

    Check out the latest enhancements to existing content

    See what's popular in the community right now

    Find out which releases are hitting the top charts this month

    Browse our most popular downloads to date
    
    ### New Categories

    ### Popular Categories

* [Sceneries](javascript:void(0))

    Discover scenery from Global Airports to Wilderness Strips

    Discover the latest additions to our library

    Check out the latest enhancements to existing content

    See what's popular in the community right now

    Gateway to the world: Experience International Airport add-ons

    Urban Landscapes reimagined: Explore city scenery add-ons

    Your World, enhanced: Navigate our Scenery Map to find even more content
    
    ### Countries

    ### Popular Categories

* [Others](javascript:void(0))

    Browse our complete range of flight simulation content

    Discover the latest additions to our library

    Discover the latest additions to our aircraft collection

    See what's popular in the community right now

    Explore diverse helicopter models for an elevated flying experience

    Diverse fleet of civilian aircraft for flight simulation

    Customize your ground services with detailed GSX profiles

    Essential flight checklists for safe and efficient aircraft operation
    
    ### More Categories

* [Collections](javascript:void(0))

    View the most recent collections

    A wide range of authentic airplane liveries

    Immersive Environmental Upgrades

    Indispensable add-ons

    Editor's Choice: Top Monthly Add-Ons

    Community Choice: Best Add-Ons 2023
    
* [Store](javascript:void(0))

    Latest Products in the Skies

    Browse through all available categories

    Discover our partners and developers

    Explore Community Favorites

    Fly More and Spend Less

    Latest Update Arrivals

    All add-ons on our comprehensive map

* [Requests](javascript:void(0))

    Submit your custom livery design requests here

    Propose new sceneries for development

    Track the progress of requests you're interested in

    Discover the latest fulfilled requests

* Login

### Discover

Privacy Policy
==============

It is this Platform's policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our website.

1\. General
-----------

The following notices provide a simple overview of what happens to your personal data when you visit this website. Personal data is any data by which you can be personally identified. For detailed information on data protection, please refer to our privacy statement listed below this text. 

This Platform respects your privacy with respect to all information we collect while operating our website. Accordingly, we have developed this Privacy Policy to help you understand how we collect, use, communicate, disclose, and otherwise utilize personal information. We have set forth our privacy policy below. Protecting your privacy is a high priority for us. The following privacy statement is intended to inform you about our handling of the collection, use and disclosure of personal data.This website and its services (hereinafter referred to as "we", "website", "platform", "Flightsim. to" or "Data Controller") is a provider of an e-commerce system for the online sale of products and a provider of a service for uploading and downloading free digital content accessible to everyone. This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which this website collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a "user") and customers (each, a "customer") of the website. For purposes of this Website, the "User" is any person who uses this Website, including subscribers to our newsletter and registered users, and the "Customer" is any person who has registered on the Website. The terms of this Privacy Policy apply to you whenever you access the content and/or services we provide, regardless of what device (computer, cell phone, tablet, television, etc.) you use.

### Who is responsible for data collection on this website?

Data processing on this website is carried out by the website operator. You can find the contact details in the section “**Responsible Data Controller**” in this data protection declaration.

### How do we collect your data?

On the one hand, your data is collected when you communicate it to us. This can be e.g. are data that you enter in a contact form or that you transmit when creating a user account. We collect and process personal data to the extent required in accordance with Article 6 paragraph 1 letter b GDPR if you inform us of this when opening a customer account on our website. The data required to open a customer account can be found in the input mask of the corresponding form on our website. You have the option of deleting your customer account at any time by sending us a message to the above address of the person responsible. After your customer account has been deleted, your data will be deleted provided that all contracts concluded have been completed in full, there are no legal retention periods to the contrary and there is no legitimate interest on our part in further storage.

Other data is collected automatically or after your consent when visiting the website by our IT systems. These are mainly technical data (e. B. Internet browser, operating system or time of page view). The collection of this data takes place automatically as soon as you enter this website. When you visit our website, we store by default your IP address, the website from which you visit us (referrer), the websites you visit on our site, as well as the date and duration of the visit, the browser type, browser settings and your operating system. This data is used by us exclusively to ensure the proper operation of our website and is automatically deleted after 30 days. This data is collected automatically as soon as you enter this website. In addition, we store personal data if you provide it to us yourself, for example, when filling out online forms, when you send us a message via the contact page or when you purchase a product. In these cases, we ask you for certain personal data that are necessary for the provision of the service.

### What do we use your data for?

Some of the data is collected in order to ensure that the website is provided without errors. Other data may be used to analyze your user behavior. In summary, we collect personal data for the following reasons: When it is necessary for the performance of our agreement or contractual relationship to provide a service with you is; if it is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject;  if it is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate and legal interests of us or a third party, provided that your legitimate interests or rights do not take precedence; or if you have consented to it.

### **What data do we collect?**

When you set up an account with Flightsim.to, we record, among other things, your specially created username, your e-mail address and your IP address. You must also choose a password. This information is required to register a platform user account. However, it is not necessary to provide or use your real name to set up a platform user account. Personal data is also collected if it is explicitly provided by you or transmitted as part of communication with other people on the platform. This includes community forums, chats, and feedback and other user-generated content. The personal information we collect may include the following information:

* Information you post, comment on, or follow on any of our content and services;
* Information you sent in chat;
* Information you provide when you request information or support from us, or purchase content and services from us, including information necessary to process your orders with the relevant payment merchant.

In order to provide services, we need to collect, store and use various information about your activities with our content and services. This includes, for example, which files you downloaded and when, and which files or other users you follow on our platform.

### What rights do you have regarding your data?

You have the right at any time to receive information free of charge about the origin, recipient and purpose of your stored personal data. You also have the right to request the correction or deletion of this data. If you have given your consent to data processing, you may revoke this consent at any time for the future. In addition, you have the right to request the restriction of the processing of your personal data under certain circumstances. Furthermore, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the competent supervisory authority.

You can contact us at any time about this and other questions on the subject of data protection.

### Analytics tools and third-party tools

When visiting this website, your surfing behavior may be statistically analyzed. This is done primarily with so-called analysis programs. Detailed information on these analysis programs can be found in the following data protection statement.

2\. Hosting und Content Delivery Networks
-----------------------------------------

This site uses a so-called "Content Delivery Network" (CDN) for the integration of assets into this website. A CDN is a service that enables the content of our online offer, in particular large media files such as graphics or scripts, to be delivered more quickly with the help of regionally distributed servers connected via the Internet. User data is processed exclusively for the aforementioned purposes and to maintain the security and functionality of the CDN. For this purpose, the browser you use must establish a connection to the servers of the CDN. This gives them knowledge that our website has been accessed via your IP address. The use is based on our legitimate interests, i.e. interest in a secure and efficient provision, analysis and optimization of our online offer in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. We host the content of our website with the following providers:

### Hetzner

The provider is Hetzner Online GmbH, Industriestr. 25, 91710 Gunzenhausen (hereinafter Hetzner). Details can be found in Hetzner's data protection declaration: [https://www.hetzner.com/de/rechts/datenschutz](https://www.hetzner.com/de/%20legal/data-protection). The use of Hetzner is based on Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. We have a legitimate interest in the most reliable presentation of our website. If a corresponding consent has been requested, the processing is carried out exclusively on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR and § 25 para. 1 TTDSG, insofar as the consent includes the storage of cookies or access to information in the user's terminal device (e.g. device fingerprinting) within the meaning of the TTDSG. The consent can be revoked at any time.

#### Contract Processing

We have concluded a contract about order processing (AVV) for the use of the above service. This is a contract required by data protection law, which ensures that this processes the personal data of our website visitors only according to our instructions and in compliance with the GDPR.

### External Hosting

This website is hosted externally. The personal data collected on this website is stored on the servers of the hoster(s). This can be v. a. IP addresses, contact requests, meta and communication data, contract data, contact data, names, website accesses and other data generated about a website. The external hosting is carried out for the purpose of contract fulfillment vis-à-vis our potential and existing customers (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR) and in the interest of a secure, fast and efficient provision of our online offer by a professional provider (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR). If a corresponding consent has been requested, the processing is carried out exclusively on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR and § 25 para. 1 TTDSG, insofar as the consent includes the storage of cookies or access to information in the user's terminal device (e.g. device fingerprinting) within the meaning of the TTDSG. The consent can be revoked at any time.

Our hoster(s) will process your data only to the extent necessary to fulfill its obligations to perform and follow our instructions with respect to such data.

We use the following hoster(s):

* (a) Cloudways Ltd., Junction Business Centre, 1st Floor Sqaq Lourdes, St Julians STJ3334, Malta
* (b) DigitalOcean, LLC, 101 Avenue of the Americas, 10th Floor, New York 10013, United States
* (c) BunnyWay d.o.o., Cesta komandanta Staneta 4A, 1215 Medvode, Slovenia
* (d) Cloudflare, Inc., 101 Townsend St, San Francisco, CA 94107,United States
* (e) Sendinblue GmbH, Köpenicker Street 126,10179 Berlin, Germany
* (f) Mailgun Technologies, Inc., 112 E Pecan St, #1135, San Antonio, TX, 78205
* (g) Quantcast, 795 Folsom Street San Francisco, CA 94107
* (h) LiveChat, Inc. 101 Arch Street, 8th Floor, Boston MA 02110, United States of America 

#### Contract Processing

We have concluded a contract about order processing (AVV) for the use of the above services. This is a contract required by data protection law, which ensures that this processes the personal data of our website visitors only according to our instructions and in compliance with the GDPR.

### Cloudflare

We use the service „Cloudflare“. The provider is Cloudflare Inc, 101 Townsend St, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA (hereinafter „Cloudflare”). Cloudflare offers a globally distributed content delivery network with DNS. This technically routes the transfer of information between your browser and our website üover Cloudflare's network. This enables Cloudflare to analyze the traffic between your browser and our website and to serve as a filter between our servers and potentially malicious traffic from the Internet. In doing so, Cloudflare may also use cookies or other technologies to recognize Internet users, but these are used solely for the purpose described herein.

The use of Cloudflare is based on our legitimate interest in providing our website as error-free and secure as possible (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR). The transfer of data to the USA is based on the standard contractual clauses of the EU Commission. Information can be found here: [https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/). For more information about security and privacy at Cloudflare, click here: [https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/).

#### Contract Processing

We have concluded a contract about order processing (AVV) for the use of the above service. This is a contract required by data protection law, which ensures that this processes the personal data of our website visitors only according to our instructions and in compliance with the GDPR.

### BunnyWay d.o.o.

On our website we use the Content Delivery Network ("CDN") called "Bunny" provided by BUNNYWAY d.o.o., Cesta komandanta Staneta 4A, 1215 Medvode, Slovenia ("Bunny"). Bunny is an online service that serves to deliver large media files such as graphics, page content or scripts through a network of regionally distributed and Internet-connected servers. This helps us to optimize the loading speed of our website. Bunny does not interact with the visitors of our website and does not process any personal data of visitors. Should processing nevertheless occur in individual cases, this is carried out on the basis of our legitimate interest in a secure and efficient provision, as well as improving the stability and functionality of our website in accordance with Article 6 paragraph 1 lit. f GDPR. For more information about Bunny's processing of personal data, see Bunny's privacy policy at: [https://bunny.net/privacy](https://bunny.net/privacy).

3\. General Notes and Mandatory Information
-------------------------------------------

### Privacy

The operators of these pages take the protection of your personal data very seriously. We treat your personal data confidentially and in accordance with the statutory data protection regulations and this privacy statement. When you use this website, various personal data are collected. Personal data is data with which you can be personally identified. This privacy statement explains what data we collect and how we use it. It also explains how and for what purpose this is done. We point out that the data transmission on the Internet (for example, when communicating by e-mail) may have security gaps. A gapless protection of data against access by third parties is not possible.

### Responsible Data Controller

The responsible party for data processing on this website is:

Sepehr Habashi  
Flightsim E-Commerce  
Carl-Zeiss-Straße 9  
55129 Mainz  
Germany

Telephone: +49 162 4043122  
E-Mail: [\[email protected\]](https://flightsim.to/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Controller is the natural or legal person who alone or jointly with others üdecides on the purposes and means of the processing of personal data (eg names, e-mail addresses etc.).

### Storage period

Unless a more specific storage period has been mentioned within this privacy statement, your personal data will remain with us until the purpose for the data processing no longer applies. If you assert a legitimate request for deletion or revoke your consent to data processing, your data will be deleted unless we have other legally permissible reasons for storing your personal data (e.g. retention periods under tax or commercial law); in the latter case, deletion will take place after these reasons no longer apply. As a rule, we only store your data for as long as is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the information is collected and processed.

### General information on the legal basis for data processing on this website

If you have consented to data processing, we process your personal data on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR or Art. 9 para. 2 lit. a GDPR, if special categories of data are processed according to Art. 9 para. 1 GDPR. In case of an explicit consent to the transfer of personal data to third countries, the data processing is also based on Art. 49 (1) (a) GDPR. If you have consented to the storage of cookies or to the access to information in your terminal device (e.g. via device fingerprinting), the data processing will also be carried out on the basis of Section 25 (1) TTDSG. This consent can be revoked at any time. If your data is required for the performance of a contract or for the implementation of pre-contractual measures, we process your data on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR. Furthermore, we process your data if this is necessary for the fulfillment of a legal obligation on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c GDPR. Furthermore, the data processing may be based on our legitimate interest according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. About the respective in each case relevant legal basis is informed in the following paragraphs of this privacy statement.

### Note on data transfer to the USA and other third countries

We use, among other things, tools from companies based in the USA or other third countries that are not secure under data protection law. If these tools are active, your personal data may be transferred to these third countries and processed there. We would like to point out that no level of data protection comparable to that in the EU can be guaranteed in these countries. For example, US companies are obliged to hand over personal data to security authorities without you as the data subject being able to take legal action against this. Therefore, it cannot be ruled out that U.S. authorities (e.g. intelligence services) may process, evaluate and permanently store your data on U.S. servers for monitoring purposes. We have no influence on these processing activities.

### Revocation of your consent to data processing

Many data processing operations are only possible with your express consent. You can revoke your consent at any time. The legality of the data processing carried out until the revocation remains unaffected by the revocation.

### Right of objection to data collection in special cases and to direct marketing (Art. 21 GDPR)

WHEN DATA PROCESSING IS BASED ON ART. 6 ABS. 1 LIT. E OR F GDPR, YOU HAVE THE RIGHT AT ANY TIME TO OBJECT TO THE PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA FOR REASONS ARISING FROM YOUR PARTICULAR SITUATION; THIS ALSO APPLIES TO PROFILING BASED ON THESE PROVISIONS. THE ANY LEGAL BASIS ON WHICH ANY PROCESSING IS BASED, YOU EXCEPT FROM THIS DATA PROTECTION STATEMENT. IF YOU DISAGREE, WE WILL NO LONGER PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA CONCERNED, UNLESS WE CAN PROVIDE REASONABLE PRIVACY REASONS; R THE PROCESSING THAT AFFECT YOUR INTERESTS, RIGHTS AND FREEDOMS OR THAT THE PROCESSING IS FOR THE PURPOSE OF ENFORCING, EXTORTING OR DEFENDING RIGHTS CLAIMS (COMPLAINT UNDER ART. 21 ABS. 1 GDPR).

If YOUR PERSONAL DATA IS PROCESSED FOR THE PURPOSE OF DIRECT ADVERTISING, YOU HAVE THE RIGHT TO OBJECT AT ANY TIME TO THE PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA FOR THE PURPOSE OF SUCH ADVERTISING; THIS ALSO APPLIES TO PROFILING, TO THE EXTENT THAT IT IS RELATED TO SUCH DIRECT ADVERTISING. IF YOU DISAGREE, YOUR PERSONAL DATA WILL FURTHER NOT BE USED FOR THE PURPOSE OF DIRECT ADVERTISING (DISCLAIMER IN ACCORDANCE WITH ART. 21 ABS. 2 GDPR).

### Right of complaint to the competent supervisory authority

In the event of violations of the GDPR, the data subjects shall have a right of appeal to a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of their habitual residence, their place of work or the place of the suspected violation. The right of appeal is without prejudice to any other administrative or judicial remedy.

### Right to data portability

You have the right to have data that we process automatically on the basis of your consent or in performance of a contract handed over to you or to a third party in a valid, machine-readable format. If you request the direct transfer of the data to another controller, this will only be done insofar as it is technically feasible.

### Information, correction and deletion

You have, within the framework of the applicable legal provisions at any time the right to free information über your stored personal data, their origin and recipient and the purpose of data processing and, if necessary, a right to rectification or deletion of this data. For this purpose, as well as for further questions on the subject of personal data, you can contact us at any time.

### Right to restrict processing

You have the right to request the restriction of the processing of your personal data. For this purpose, you can contact us at any time. The right to restriction of processing exists in the following cases:

* If you dispute the accuracy of your personal data stored by us, we usually need time to verify this. For the duration of the examination, you have the right to request that the processing of your personal data be restricted.
* If the processing of your personal data was/is unlawful, you can request the restriction of data processing instead of deletion.
* If we no longer need your personal data, but you need it to exercise, defend or assert legal claims, you have the right to have the processing of your data restricted instead of deleted to request personal data.
* If you have lodged an objection in accordance with Art. 21 (1) GDPR, your interests and ours must be weighed up. As long as it has not yet been determined whose interests prevail, you have the right to request that the processing of your personal data be restricted.

If you have restricted the processing of your personal data, these data may be processed – apart from their storage – only with your consent or for the assertion, exercise or defense of legal claims or for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person or for reasons of an important public interest of the European Union or a Member State.

### SSL or TLS encryption

This site uses SSL or TLS encryption for security reasons and to protect the transmission of confidential content, such as orders or requests that you send to us as the site operator. You can recognize an encrypted connection by the fact that the address line of the browser changes from „http://“ to „https://“ and by the lock symbol in your browser line.

When SSL or TLS encryption is enabled, the data you send to us cannot be read by third parties.

### Encrypted payment transactions on this website

If, after the conclusion of a contract with costs, there is an obligation to provide us with your payment data (e.g. account number in the case of direct debit authorization), this data is required for payment processing.

The payment transactions via the common means of payment (Visa/MasterCard, direct debit) are carried out exclusively via an encrypted SSL or TLS connection. You can recognize an encrypted connection by the fact that the address line of the browser changes from „http://“ to „https://“ and by the lock symbol in your browser line.

With encrypted communication, your payment data that you send to us cannot be read by third parties.

### Objection to promotional emails

The use of contact data published within the framework of the imprint obligation for the purpose of sending unsolicited advertising and information materials is hereby prohibited. The operators of the sites expressly reserve the right to take legal action in the case of unsolicited promotional information, such as spam e-mails.

4\. Data collection on this Website
-----------------------------------

### Advertising

This website is associated with Freestar to serve advertisements on the website and Freestar will collect and use certain information for advertising purposes if you consent. This happens if you actively choose to accept the cookie prompt. In this case, usage data is tracked for so-called usage-based online advertising, i.e. usage data is collected and processed pseudonymously into usage profiles ("advertising tracking"). This happens because advertisers need reliable information in order to advertise online as efficiently as possible, in particular about how many readers see their ads and which users estimate which products, topics or offers are of particular interest. We only use advertising tracking on our site with your express consent. Your consent will therefore be requested before the website is accessed. The legal basis for the use of advertising tracking and the setting of any cookies required for this is Article 6(1)(a) GDPR. To learn more about Freestar's use of data, click here: [https://freestar.com/privacy-policy/](https://freestar.com/privacy-policy/). 

**You can revoke your consent to advertising tracking at any time** by clicking on "change consent" in the navigation bar on the bottom right of the website. ("Change Consent"), delete your browser cookies yourself, or by clicking here: [Change cookie settings](javascript:void(0)). You can find more information about cookies and their use in the following section.

### Cookies

Our Internet pages use so-called „cookies“. Cookies are small data packets and do not cause any damage to your end device. They are stored either temporarily for the duration of a session (session cookies) or permanently (permanent cookies) on your end device. Session cookies are automatically deleted at the end of your visit. Permanent cookies remain stored on your end device until you delete them yourself or until they are automatically deleted by your web browser.

Cookies can originate from us (first-party cookies) or from third-party companies (so-called third-party cookies). Third-party cookies enable the integration of certain services of third-party companies within websites (e.g. cookies for the processing of payment services).

Cookies have various functions. Many cookies are technically necessary, as certain website functions would not work without them (e. g. the shopping cart function or the display of videos). Other cookies can be used to evaluate user behavior or for advertising purposes.

Cookies that are required to carry out the electronic communication process, to provide certain functions you have requested (e.g. for the shopping cart function) or to optimize the website (e.g. cookies to measure the web audience) (necessary cookies) are stored on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR, unless another legal basis is specified. The website operator has a legitimate interest in storing necessary cookies for the technically error-free and optimized provision of its services. Insofar as consent to the storage of cookies and comparable recognition technologies has been requested, the processing is carried out exclusively on the basis of this consent (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR and § 25 para. 1 TTDSG); the consent can be revoked at any time. 

You can set your browser so that you are informed about the setting of cookies and allow cookies only in individual cases, the acceptance of cookies for certain cases or generally exclude as well as activate the automatic deletion of cookies when closing the browser. When disabling cookies, the functionality of this website may be limited.

To improve the quality and functionality of our websites and in case of prosecution, we store data über individual accesses to our pages for statistical purposes. This data record consists of: the page from which the file was requested, the name of the file, the date and time of the request, the amount of data transferred, the access status (file transferred, file not found), the description of the type of web browser used, the IP address of the requesting computer. This data is used exclusively to ensure the smooth operation of our website and to improve our services. It is not possible to assign this data to a specific person. The legal basis for this data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR (legitimate interests of the responsible party). The above-mentioned reasons also constitute the legitimate interest for data processing pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR.

Platform for consent management: With the data protection options, we offer you the opportunity to decide for yourself in detail in which cases you want to be tracked using cookies and other technologies - for the purpose of displaying content that is relevant to you and advertising tailored to you - wish to agree. The processing of your data for the above purposes is partly based on a legitimate interest, but partly we also need your consent. In order to ensure the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and to offer you as a user a maximum of to provide transparency, we participate in the Transparency & Consent Framework (TCF) of the IAB Europe and subject us to its specifications and guidelines. For this we use the Consent Management Platform (CMP) Quantcast, 795 Folsom Street San Francisco, CA 94107 as a processor. Quantcast uses so-called standard contractual clauses (= Art. 46 Para. 2 and 3 DSGVO) as the basis for data processing for recipients based in third countries, in particular in the USA, or for data transmission there. These clauses are templates provided by the EU Commission and are intended to ensure that your data also complies with European data protection standards when transferred to third countries (such as the USA) and there get saved. Quantcast undertakes through the clauses to comply with European data protection standards when processing your relevant data, even if the data is stored in the USA, processed and managed. The standard contractual clauses are based on an implementation decision of the EU Commission, which you can find here, among other places: [https://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/dec\_impl/2021/914/oj?locale=de](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/dec_impl/2021/914/oj?locale=de). Quantcast's CMP enables you to give us data protection-compliant and self-determined consent to the processing of your data and to revoke this at any time. You can also object to data processing on the basis of our legitimate interest.

In the event that you visit other websites through the links displayed on this website, we encourage you to read the privacy policies published on those websites. We use third parties to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or phone number) about your visits to this and other websites to provide you with advertisements for goods and services, that interest you. If you would like more information about this practice and the choices you have to prevent these companies from using this information, [click here](https://optout.networkadvertising.org /?c=1). 

Common browsers offer the setting option not to allow cookies. You can set your browser so that you are informed about the setting of cookies and only allow cookies in individual cases, exclude the acceptance of cookies or activate the automatic deletion of cookies when closing the browser. There is no guarantee that you will be able to use all the functions of this website without restriction if you make the appropriate settings. For more information, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) or [www.allaboutcookies.org](http: //www.allaboutcookies.org). You can set your browser to not accept cookies, and the above websites will tell you how to remove cookies from your browser. However, in a few cases, this may cause some features of our website not to work.

We use cookies to help you navigate efficiently and perform certain functions. You will find detailed information about all cookies under each consent category below. The cookies that are categorized as "Necessary" are stored on your browser as they are essential for enabling the basic functionalities of the site. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze how you use this website, store your preferences, and provide the content and advertisements that are relevant to you. These cookies will only be stored in your browser with your prior consent. You can choose to enable or disable some or all of these cookies but disabling some of them may affect your browsing experience: [Change cookie settings](javascript:void(0))

**Necessary**

Necessary cookies are required to enable the basic features of this site, such as providing secure log-in or adjusting your consent preferences. These cookies do not store any personally identifiable data.

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| PHPSESSID | .flightsim.to | Session | This cookie is native to PHP applications. The cookie is used to store and identify a users' unique session ID for the purpose of managing user session on the website. The cookie is a session cookies and is deleted when all the browser windows are closed. |
| cf\_use\_ob | cdn.flightsim.to | Session | Cloudflare sets this cookie to improve page load times and to disallow any security restrictions based on the visitor's IP address. |
| \_\_cfruid | .discord.com | Session | Cloudflare sets this cookie to identify trusted web traffic. |
| \_\_cflb | .flightsim.to | 7 days | This cookie is used by Cloudflare for load balancing and delivering the service. |
| fs.bot.check | .flightsim.to | Session | This cookie is used to detect malicious bots. |

**Functional**

Functional cookies help perform certain functionalities like sharing the content of the website on social media platforms, collecting feedback, and other third-party features.

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| \_\_sharethis\_cookie\_test\_\_ | flightsim.to | Session | ShareThis sets this cookie to track which pages are being shared and by whom. |
| \_\_cf\_bm | .flightsim.to | 4 hours | This cookie, set by Cloudflare, is used to support Cloudflare Bot Management. |
| site\_language | .flightsim.to | 14 days | This cookie is used to determine and save the user's preferred site language. |
| remember\_me | .flightsim.to | Session | This cookie is set to remember the user's current session and keep them logged in when the browser has been closed. |

**Analytics**

Analytical cookies are used to understand how visitors interact with the website. These cookies help provide information on metrics such as the number of visitors, bounce rate, traffic source, etc.

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Cookie Name | Description | Duration |
| \_ga\_\* | Google Analytics sets this cookie to store and count page views. | 1 year 1 month 4 days |
| \_ga | The \_ga cookie, installed by Google Analytics, calculates visitor, session and campaign data and also keeps track of site usage for the site's analytics report. The cookie stores information anonymously and assigns a randomly generated number to recognize unique visitors. | 1 year 1 month 4 days |
| \_\_gads | The \_\_gads cookie, set by Google, is stored under DoubleClick domain and tracks the number of times users see an advert, measures the success of the campaign and calculates its revenue. This cookie can only be read from the domain they are set on and will not track any data while browsing through other sites. | Session |
| \_gcl\_au | Provided by Google Tag Manager to experiment advertisement efficiency of websites using their services. | Session |
| \_gid | Installed by Google Analytics, \_gid cookie stores information on how visitors use a website, while also creating an analytics report of the website's performance. Some of the data that are collected include the number of visitors, their source, and the pages they visit anonymously. | Session |
| \_gat\_gtag\_UA\_\* | Google Analytics sets this cookie to store a unique user ID. | Session |

**Performance**

Performance cookies are used to understand and analyze the key performance indexes of the website which helps in delivering a better user experience for the visitors.

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| \_gat | This cookie is installed by Google Universal Analytics to restrain request rate and thus limit the collection of data on high traffic sites. | 1 Minute |

**Advertisement**

Advertisement cookies are used to provide visitors with customized advertisements based on the pages you visited previously and to analyze the effectiveness of the ad campaigns.

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| \_\_qca | The \_\_qca cookie is associated with Quantcast. This anonymous data helps us to better understand users' needs and customize the website accordingly. | Session |
| \_cc\_id | The cookie is set by crwdcntrl.net to collect statistical data such as the number of visits, average time spent on site, and what pages have been loaded, for targeted advertising. | Session |
| cto\_bundle | Criteo set this cookie to send anonymous statistics for advertising. | Session |
| \_\_gpi | Google Ads Service uses this cookie to collect information about from multiple websites for retargeting ads. | Session |
| \_dlt | Zendesk set this cookie to create a unique ID for the session. This enables the website to collect data on visitor behaviour for statistical purposes. | Session |
| \_fbp | This cookie is set by Facebook to display advertisements when either on Facebook or on a digital platform powered by Facebook advertising, after visiting the website. | Session |
| cto\_bidid | Criteo sets this cookie to gather visitor data to show more relevant advertising. | Session |
| \_cc\_cc | The cookie is set by crwdcntrl.net to collect statistical data such as the number of visits, average time spent on site, and what pages have been loaded, for targeted advertising. | Session |
| test\_cookie | The test\_cookie is set by doubleclick.net and is used to determine if the user's browser supports cookies. | 15 Minutes |
| YSC | YSC cookie is set by Youtube and is used to track the views of embedded videos on Youtube pages. | Session |
| VISITOR\_INFO1\_LIVE | A cookie set by YouTube to measure bandwidth that determines whether the user gets the new or old player interface. | 5 months 27 days |
| yt-remote-device-id | YouTube sets this cookie to store the video preferences of the user using embedded YouTube video. | never |
| yt-remote-connected-devices | YouTube sets this cookie to store the video preferences of the user using embedded YouTube video. | never |
| yt.innertube::nextId | This cookie, set by YouTube, registers a unique ID to store data on what videos from YouTube the user has seen. | never |
| yt.innertube::requests | This cookie, set by YouTube, registers a unique ID to store data on what videos from YouTube the user has seen. | never |

### Server log files

The provider of the pages automatically collects and stores information in so-called server log files, which your browser automatically transmits to us. These are:

* Browser type and browser version
* Operating system used
* Referrer URL
* Hostname of the accessing computer
* Time of server request
* IP address

This data is not merged with other data sources.

The collection of this data takes place on the basis of Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in the technically error-free presentation and optimization of his website - to do this, the server log files must be recorded.

### Contact form

If you send us inquiries via the contact form, your details from the inquiry form, including the contact details you provided there, will be stored by us for the purpose of processing the inquiry and in the event of follow-up questions. We will not pass on this data without your consent.  Our contact form is provided and hosted by: LiveChat, Inc. 101 Arch Street, 8th Floor, Boston MA 02110, United States of America. LiveChat, Inc. stores the information you provide when submitting the contact form. 

This data is processed on the basis of Article 6 Paragraph 1 Letter b GDPR if your request is related to the fulfillment of a contract or is required to carry out pre-contractual measures. In all other cases, the processing is based on our legitimate interest in the effective processing of inquiries addressed to us (Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f GDPR) or on your consent (Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. a GDPR) , if you wish; consent can be revoked at any time.

We process your data with the help of LiveChat Inc. for the purpose of processing contact requests and their processing in accordance with Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR. The legal basis for the use and order processing by LiveChat Inc. is also our legitimate interest in optimized customer service in accordance with Article 6 Paragraph 1 Letter f) GDPR.

The data you enter in the contact form will remain with us until you ask us to delete it, revoke your consent to storage or the purpose for data storage no longer applies (e.g. after your Inquiry). Mandatory Legal Provisions - in particular retention periods - remain untouched.

### Inquiry by e-mail, telephone or fax

If you contact us by e-mail, telephone or fax, your request, including all personal data resulting from it (name, request) will be stored and processed by us for the purpose of processing your request. We do not pass on this data without your consent. Our mail server is provided and hosted by: LiveChat, Inc. 101 Arch Street, 8th Floor, Boston MA 02110, United States of America. LiveChat, Inc. collects the information you provide when you contact us via email.

This data is processed on the basis of Article 6 Paragraph 1 Letter b GDPR if your request is related to the fulfillment of a contract or is necessary to carry out pre-contractual measures. In all other cases, the processing is based on our legitimate interest in the effective processing of inquiries addressed to us (Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f GDPR) or on your consent (Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. a GDPR) if requested; the consent can be revoked at any time.

The data you sent to us via contact requests will remain with us until you ask us to delete it, revoke your consent to storage or the purpose for data storage no longer applies (e.g.  after your request has been processed). Mandatory Legal Provisions - in particular statutory retention periods - remain untouched.

### OpenAI

To to make our support resources and workflow more efficient, we use artificial intelligence services and products provided by OpenAI, L.L.C - 3180 18th St San Francisco, CA 94110 - United States. This service enables us to answer support inquiries by Contact form or e-mail (as described above) more quickly and efficiently. When you use our Contact form or send us an email to our official support emails, your queries and associated data - such the information you give - might be passed to OpenAI for processing. This data is processed on the basis of Article 6 Paragraph 1 Letter b GDPR. OpenAI is located in the United States. Data is therefore transferred to a third country. However, OpenAI has put in place appropriate safeguards to ensure the security of your data. These include compliance with the standard contractual clauses approved by the EU Commission for the transfer of personal data to third countries. In this regard, we have executed an Data Processing Addendum with OpenAI.

### Registration on this website

You can register on this website to use additional functions on the site. We use the data entered for this purpose only for the purpose of using the respective offer or service for which you have registered. The mandatory information requested during registration must be provided in full. Otherwise, we will reject the registration.

For important changes, for example in the scope of the offer or for technically necessary changes, we use the e-mail address provided during registration to inform you in this way.

The processing of the data entered during registration is carried out for the purpose of implementing the user relationship established by registration and, if necessary, for the initiation of further contracts (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR).

The data collected during registration will be stored by us as long as you are registered on this website and will subsequently be deleted. Legal retention periods remain unaffected.

### Comment function on this website

For the comment function on this site, in addition to your comment, information on the time of creation of the comment, your e-mail address and, if you do not post anonymously, the username you have chosen will be stored. This website uses the service Hyvor Talk as a platform for comments. Hyvor Talk is operated by HYVOR, 11 RUE CARNOT 94270, LE KREMLIN-BICETRE France. The comments and other data exchanged are stored securely in Hyvor Talk's system. Your personal data will be processed and Übermitted in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). For more information, please refer to HYVOR's privacy policy. We use the single sign-on feature of Hyvor Talk to connect our users to the commenting system. Your account information is used when you choose to comment. When the comment element is active, a direct connection is established between your terminal device and Hyvor Talk's servers. Hyvoer Talk receives the information that you have visited this website with your IP address. If consent is given, the above service is provided on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR and § 25 TTDSG. The consent can be revoked at any time. If there is no consent, the use of the service is based on our legitimate interest in effective business processing.

#### Storage of IP address

Our comment function stores the IP addresses of users who post comments. Since we do not check comments on this website before they are activated, we need this data in order to be able to take action against the author in the event of legal violations such as insults or propaganda.

#### Duration of storage of comments

The comments and the associated data are stored and remain on this website until the commented content has been completely deleted or the comments have to be deleted for legal reasons (e.g. offensive comments).

#### Legal basis

The storage of comments is based on your consent (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR). You can revoke any consent you have given at any time. For this purpose, an informal communication by e-mail to us is sufficient. The legality of the data processing already carried out remains unaffected by the revocation.

5\. Social Media
----------------

**This data protection declaration also applies to the following social media appearances:**

#### **Data processing by social networks**

We maintain publicly accessible profiles on social networks. The individual social networks we use can be found below.

Social networks such as Facebook, Twitter etc. can usually analyze your user behavior comprehensively if you visit their website or a website with integrated social media content (e.g. Like buttons or advertising banners). . Visiting our social media sites triggers numerous data protection-related processing operations. In detail:

If you are logged into your social media account and visit our social media presence, the operator of the social media portal can assign this visit to your user account. However, your personal data may also be recorded if you are not logged in or do not have an account with the respective social media portal. In this case, this data is collected, for example, via cookies that are stored on your end device or by recording your IP address.

With the help of the data collected in this way, the operators of the social media portals can create user profiles in which your preferences and interests are stored. In this way, you can be shown interest-based advertising inside and outside of the respective social media presence. If you have an account with the respective social network, interest-based advertising can be displayed on all devices on which you are logged in or were logged in.

Please also note that we cannot trace all processing operations on the social media portals. Depending on the provider, additional processing operations may therefore be carried out by the operators of the social media portals. Details can be found in the terms of use and data protection regulations of the respective social media portals.

#### **Legal Basis**

Our social media presence is intended to ensure the widest possible presence on the internet. This is a legitimate interest within the meaning of Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The analysis processes initiated by the social networks may be based on different legal bases, which must be specified by the operators of the social networks (e.g. consent within the meaning of Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. a GDPR).

#### **Person responsible and assertion of rights**

If you visit one of our social media presences (e.g. Facebook), we are jointly responsible with the operator of the social media platform for the data processing operations triggered during this visit. You can fundamentally exercise your rights (information, correction, deletion, restriction of processing, data portability and complaint) both against. us as well as ggü. the operator of the respective social media portal (e.g. vs. Facebook).

Please note that despite joint responsibility with the social media portal operators, we do not have full influence on the data processing operations of the social media portals. Our options are largely based on the company policy of the respective provider.

#### **Storage period**

The data collected directly by us via the social media presence will be deleted from our systems as soon as you ask us to delete it, revoke your consent to storage or the purpose for data storage not applicable. Saved cookies remain on your end device until you delete them. Mandatory Legal Provisions - esp. retention periods - remain untouched.

We have no influence on the storage period of your data, which is stored by the operators of the social networks for their own purposes. For details, please contact the operators of the social networks directly (e.g. in their data protection declaration, see below).

#### **Your rights**

You have the right to receive information about the origin, recipient and purpose of your stored personal data free of charge at any time. You also have the right to object, to data portability and to lodge a complaint with the competent supervisory authority. You can also request the correction, blocking, deletion and, under certain circumstances, the restriction of the processing of your personal data.

### Facebook

Elements of the social network Facebook are integrated on this website. The provider of this service is Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland. According to Facebook, however, the data collected is also transferred to the USA and other third countries.

You can find an overview of the Facebook social media elements here: [https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/?locale=de\_DE](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/?locale=de_DE).

If the social media element is active, a direct connection will be established between your end device and the Facebook server. Facebook receives the information that you have visited this website with your IP address. If you click the Facebook “Like button” click while you are logged into your Facebook account, you can link the content of this website to your Facebook profile. This allows Facebook to associate your visit to this website with your user account. We would like to point out that we, as the provider of the pages, have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted or how it is used by Facebook. You can find more information on this in Facebook's privacy policy at: [https://de-de.facebook.com/privacy/explanation](https://de-de.facebook.com/privacy/explanation).

If consent has been obtained, the above mentioned service on the basis of Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. a GDPR and § 25 TTDSG. The consent can be revoked at any time. If no consent has been obtained, the use of the service is based on our legitimate interest in the widest possible visibility in social media.

Insofar as personal data is collected on our website and forwarded to Facebook using the tool described here, we and Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland are jointly responsible for this data processing responsible (Article 26 GDPR). Joint responsibility is limited to collecting the data and passing it on to Facebook. The processing by Facebook after the forwarding is not part of the joint responsibility. Our mutual obligations have been set out in a joint processing agreement. The text of the agreement can be found at: [https:// www.facebook.com/legal/controller\_addendum](https://www.facebook.com/legal/controller_addendum). According to this agreement, we are responsible for providing data protection information when using the Facebook tool and for implementing the tool on our website in a manner that is secure under data protection law. Facebook is responsible for the data security of Facebook products. You can assert your rights (e.g. requests for information) regarding the data processed on Facebook directly on Facebook. If you assert the rights of the data subject with us, we are obliged to forward them to Facebook.

Data transfer to the USA is based on the standard contractual clauses of the EU Commission. Details can be found here: [https://www.facebook .com/legal/EU\_data\_transfer\_addendum](https://www.facebook.com/legal/EU_data_transfer_addendum), [https://de-de.facebook.com/help/566994660333381](https://de-de.facebook.com/help/566994660333381) and [https://www.facebook.com/policy.php](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php).

### Twitter

Functions of the Twitter service are integrated on this website. These features are provided by Twitter International Company, One Cumberland Place, Fenian Street, Dublin 2, D02 AX07, Ireland.

If the social media element is active, a direct connection will be established between your end device and the Twitter server. Twitter thereby receives information about your visit to this website. By using Twitter and the “Re-Tweet” the websites you visit are linked to your Twitter account and made known to other users. We would like to point out that we, as the provider of the pages, have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted or how it is used by Twitter. You can find more information on this in Twitter's privacy policy at: [https://twitter.com/de/privacy](https://twitter.com/de/privacy).

If consent has been obtained, the above mentioned service on the basis of Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. a GDPR and § 25 TTDSG. The consent can be revoked at any time. If no consent has been obtained, the use of the service is based on our legitimate interest in the widest possible visibility in social media.

Data transfer to the USA is based on the standard contractual clauses of the EU Commission. Details can be found here: [https://gdpr.twitter.com/en/controller-to-controller-transfers.html](https://gdpr.twitter.com/en/controller-to-controller-transfers.html).

Your privacy settings on Twitter can be changed in the account settings under [https://twitter.com/account/settings](https://twitter.com/account/settings).

### Instagram

Functions of the Instagram service are integrated on this website. These functions are offered by Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland.

If the social media element is active, a direct connection will be established between your end device and the Instagram server. Instagram receives information about your visit to this website.

If you are logged into your Instagram account, you can link the content of this website to your Instagram profile by clicking on the Instagram button. This allows Instagram to associate your visit to this website with your user account. We would like to point out that we, as the provider of the pages, have no knowledge of the content of the transmitted data or how it is used by Instagram.

If consent has been obtained, the above mentioned service on the basis of Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. a GDPR and § 25 TTDSG. The consent can be revoked at any time. If no consent has been obtained, the use of the service is based on our legitimate interest in the widest possible visibility in social media.

Insofar as personal data is collected on our website with the help of the tool described here and forwarded to Facebook or Instagram, we and Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland are jointly responsible for responsible for this data processing (Article 26 GDPR). Joint responsibility is limited to collecting the data and passing it on to Facebook or Instagram. The processing by Facebook or Instagram after forwarding is not part of the joint responsibility. Our mutual obligations have been set out in a joint processing agreement. The text of the agreement can be found at: [https:// www.facebook.com/legal/controller\_addendum](https://www.facebook.com/legal/controller_addendum). According to this agreement, we are responsible for issuing the data protection information when using the Facebook or Instagram tool and for implementing the tool on our website in a secure manner in accordance with data protection law. Facebook is responsible for the data security of Facebook and Instagram products. You can assert your rights (e.g. requests for information) regarding the data processed on Facebook or Instagram directly on Facebook. If you assert the rights of the data subject with us, we are obliged to forward them to Facebook.

Data transfer to the USA is based on the standard contractual clauses of the EU Commission. Details can be found here: [https://www.facebook .com/legal/EU\_data\_transfer\_addendum](https://www.facebook.com/legal/EU_data_transfer_addendum), [https:/ /help.instagram.com/519522125107875](https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875) and [https://de-de.facebook.com/help/566994660333381](https://de-de.facebook.com/help/566994660333381).

For more information, see Instagram's privacy policy: [https://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/](https://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/).

### ShareThis

Elements of ShareThis are implemented on this website. The provider of this service is ShareThis, 3000 El Camino Real Building 4, Suite 200 Palo Alto, CA 94306. ShareThis's privacy policy can be found here: [https://sharethis.com/privacy/](https://sharethis.com/privacy/). When the social media element is active, a direct connection is established between your device and the ShareThis server. ShareThis receives the information that you have visited this website with your IP address. 

If consent has been given, the above service will be provided on the basis of Article 6(1)(a) GDPR and § 25 TTDSG. The consent can be revoked at any time. If no consent has been given, the use of the service is based on our legitimate interest in the greatest possible visibility in social media.

Insofar as personal data is collected on our website using the tool described here and forwarded to ShareThis, we and ShareThis are jointly responsible for this data processing (Art. 26 GDPR). The joint responsibility is limited exclusively to collecting the data and passing it on to ShareThis. The processing by ShareThis after the transfer is not part of the joint responsibility. 

6\. Analysis tools and advertising
----------------------------------

### Google Analytics

This website uses functions of the web analysis service Google Analytics. The provider is Google Ireland Limited (“Google”), Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.

Google Analytics enables the website operator to analyze the behavior of website visitors. The website operator receives various usage data, such as e.g. Page views, length of stay, operating systems used and origin of the user. This data is assigned to the respective end device of the user. There is no assignment to a user ID.

Furthermore, we can use Google Analytics and others. Record your mouse and scroll movements and clicks. Furthermore, Google Analytics uses various modeling approaches to supplement the recorded data sets and uses machine learning technologies for data analysis.

Google Analytics uses technologies that enable the user to be recognized for the purpose of analyzing user behavior (e.g. cookies or device fingerprinting). The information collected by Google about the use of this website is usually transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there.

The use of this service is based on your consent in accordance with Article 6(1)(a) GDPR and § 25 paragraph 1 TTDSG. Consent can be revoked at any time.

Data transfer to the USA is based on the standard contractual clauses of the EU Commission. Details can be found here: [https:// privacy.google.com/businesses/controllerterms/mccs/](https://privacy.google.com/businesses/controllerterms/mccs/).

You can prevent the storage of cookies by setting your browser software accordingly; we would like to point out to you however that in this case you will if applicable not be able to use all functions of this website in full. You can also prevent Google from collecting the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website (including your IP address) and from processing this data by Google by clicking on the following link ;Download and install the available browser plugin.

You can find more information about how Google uses your data at http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/de.html and http://www.google.com/intl/de/ analytics/privacyoverview.html.

Google Analytics cookies are stored on the basis of Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize both its website and its advertising and thus also serves to finance and customer-oriented use, adaptation and updating of the website. IP anonymization is activated on this website.

#### IP anonymization

We have activated the IP anonymisation function on this website. As a result, your IP address will be shortened by Google within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states of the Agreement on the European Economic Area before it is transmitted to the USA. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be sent to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide other services related to website activity and internet usage to the website operator. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of Google Analytics will not be merged with other Google data.

#### Browser plugin

You can prevent Google’s collection and processing of your data by downloading and installing the browser plugin available at the following link: [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de](https://tools.google.com/dlpage%20/gaoptout?hl=de).

You can find more information on how Google Analytics handles user data in Google's privacy policy: [https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en).

#### Demographic characteristics in Google Analytics

This website uses the “demographic characteristics” by Google Analytics in order to be able to show website visitors relevant advertisements within the Google advertising network. This allows reports to be created that contain statements about the age, gender and interests of the site visitors. This data comes from interest-based advertising from Google and visitor data from third-party providers. This data cannot be assigned to a specific person. You can deactivate this function at any time via the ad settings in your Google account or the collection of your data by Google Analytics as described in the point “Objection to data collection” generally prohibited.

#### Order processing

We have concluded an order processing contract with Google and fully implement the strict requirements of the German data protection authorities when using Google Analytics.

#### Google Analytics E-Commerce Measurement

This website uses the “E-Commerce Measurement” by Google Analytics. With the help of e-commerce measurement, the website operator can analyze the purchasing behavior of website visitors to improve their online marketing campaigns. Information such as the orders placed, average order values, shipping costs and the time from viewing a product to purchasing it are recorded. This data can be summarized by Google under a transaction ID that is assigned to the respective user or their device.

### Google Ads

The website operator uses Google Ads. Google Ads is an online advertising program from Google Ireland Limited („Google”), Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.

Google Ads enables us to display advertisements in the Google search engine or on third-party websites when the user enters certain search terms on Google (keyword targeting). Furthermore, targeted advertisements can be displayed based on the user data available from Google (e.g. location data and interests) (target group targeting). As the website operator, we can evaluate this data quantitatively, for example by analyzing which search terms led to the display of our advertisements and how many advertisements led to corresponding clicks.

The use of this service is based on your consent in accordance with Article 6(1)(a) GDPR and § 25 paragraph 1 TTDSG. Consent can be revoked at any time.

Data transfer to the USA is based on the standard contractual clauses of the EU Commission. Details can be found here: [https://policies.google .com/privacy/frameworks](https://policies.google.com/privacy/frameworks) and [https://privacy.google.com/businesses/controllerterms/mccs/](https://privacy.google.com/businesses/controllerterms/mccs/).

### Google AdSense

This website uses Google AdSense, a service for integrating advertisements. The provider is Google Ireland Limited (“Google”), Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.

With the help of Google Adsense, we can display targeted advertisements from third-party companies on our site. The content of the advertisements is based on your interests, which Google determines based on your previous user behavior. Furthermore, when selecting the appropriate advertisement, context information such as your location, the content of the website visited or the Google search terms you entered are also taken into account.

Google AdSense uses cookies, web beacons (invisible graphics) and similar recognition technologies. This allows information such as visitor traffic on these pages to be evaluated.

The information collected by Google Adsense about the use of this website (including your IP address) and the delivery of advertising formats is transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. This information may be passed on by Google to Google's contractual partners. However, Google will not merge your IP address with other data stored by you.

The use of this service is based on your consent in accordance with Article 6(1)(a) GDPR and § 25 paragraph 1 TTDSG. Consent can be revoked at any time.

Data transfer to the USA is based on the standard contractual clauses of the EU Commission. Details can be found here: [https:// privacy.google.com/businesses/controllerterms/mccs/](https://privacy.google.com/businesses/controllerterms/mccs/).

You can prevent the installation of cookies by setting your browser software accordingly. However, we would like to point out that in this case you may not be able to use all the functions of this website to their full extent. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. Further information on data protection and cookies for Google AdSense advertising can be found in Google's data protection declaration, in particular under the following links: [http://www.google.de/policies/privacy/partners/](https://www.google.de/policies/privacy/partners%20/), [http://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/technologies/ads](http://www.google.de /intl/de/policies/technologies/ads), [https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/2839090](https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/2839090) and [https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner- sites](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites).

### Meta-Pixel (ehemals Facebook Pixel)

This website uses Facebook/Meta visitor action pixels to measure conversion. The provider of this service is Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland. According to Facebook, however, the data collected is also transferred to the USA and other third countries.

In this way, the behavior of site visitors can be tracked after they have been redirected to the provider's website by clicking on a Facebook ad. This allows the effectiveness of the Facebook ads to be evaluated for statistical and market research purposes and future advertising measures to be optimized.

The data collected is anonymous to us as the operator of this website, we cannot draw any conclusions about the identity of the user. However, the data is stored and processed by Facebook so that a connection to the respective user profile is possible and Facebook uses the data for its own advertising purposes, in accordance with the Facebook data usage guidelines ([https://de-de.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://de-de.facebook .com/about/privacy/)). . This enables Facebook to place advertisements on Facebook pages and outside of Facebook. This use of the data cannot be influenced by us as the site operator.

The use of this service is based on your consent in accordance with Article 6(1)(a) GDPR and § 25 paragraph 1 TTDSG. Consent can be revoked at any time.

Insofar as personal data is collected on our website and forwarded to Facebook using the tool described here, we and Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland are jointly responsible for this data processing responsible (Article 26 GDPR). Joint responsibility is limited to collecting the data and passing it on to Facebook. The processing by Facebook after the forwarding is not part of the joint responsibility. Our mutual obligations have been set out in a joint processing agreement. The text of the agreement can be found at: [https:// www.facebook.com/legal/controller\_addendum](https://www.facebook.com/legal/controller_addendum). According to this agreement, we are responsible for providing data protection information when using the Facebook tool and for implementing the tool on our website in a manner that is secure under data protection law. Facebook is responsible for the data security of Facebook products. You can assert your rights (e.g. requests for information) regarding the data processed by Facebook directly on Facebook. If you assert the rights of the data subject with us, we are obliged to forward them to Facebook.

Data transfer to the USA is based on the standard contractual clauses of the EU Commission. Details can be found here: [https://www.facebook .com/legal/EU\_data\_transfer\_addendum](https://www.facebook.com/legal/EU_data_transfer_addendum) and [https://de-de.facebook.com/help/566994660333381](https://de-de.facebook.com/help/566994660333381).

You can find further information on protecting your privacy in Facebook's data protection information: [https://de-de.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://de-de.facebook.com/about/privacy/).

You can also use the “Custom Audiences” in the settings for ads under [https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry\_product=ad\_settings\_screen](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen). To do this, you must be logged in to Facebook.

If you do not have a Facebook account, you can deactivate usage-based advertising from Facebook on the website of the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance: [http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/).

7\. Newsletter
--------------

### Newsletter data

If you wish to receive the newsletter offered on the website, we require an e-mail address from you as well as information that allows us to check that you are the owner of the specified e-mail address and agree to receive the newsletter. Further data is not collected or only on a voluntary basis. Für the processing of the newsletter we use newsletter service providers, which are described below. 

If you subscribe to our e-mail newsletter, we will send you regular information  about our offers. We will also send you account-related notifications via email using the email address you provided when you registered on this website.  The only mandatory information for sending the newsletter is your email address and your username on the website. The provision of further possible data is voluntary and serves to be able to address you personally.  You give us your consent to the use of your personal data pursuant to Art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR. The data we collect when you register for the newsletter will be used exclusively for the purpose of advertising via the newsletter. You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time via the link provided in the newsletter or by sending a message to the above-mentioned person responsible. After you unsubscribe, your e-mail address will be deleted from our newsletter distribution list without delay, unless you have expressly consented to the further use of your data or we reserve the right to use data in a manner that goes beyond this, which is permitted by law and about which we inform you in this declaration.

The processing of the data entered in the newsletter registration form is based exclusively on your consent (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR). You can revoke your consent to the storage of the data, the email address and its use for sending the newsletter at any time, for example by using the unsubscribe link in the newsletter. The legality of the data processing already carried out remains unaffected by the revocation.

The data stored by you for the purpose of subscribing to the newsletter will be stored by us or the newsletter service provider until you unsubscribe from the newsletter and will be deleted from the newsletter distribution list after you unsubscribe from the newsletter or after its purpose ceases to exist. We reserve the right to delete or block e-mail addresses from our newsletter distribution list at our own discretion within the scope of our legitimate interest pursuant to Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Data that we have stored for other purposes remain unaffected by this.

### Sendinblue

This website uses Sendinblue to send newsletters. Provider is Sendinblue GmbH, Köpenicker Stra;e 126, 10179 Berlin, Germany. Sendinblue is a service with which, among other things, the sending of newsletters can be organized and analyzed. The data you enter for the purpose of receiving newsletters is stored on Sendinblue's servers in Germany.

#### Data analysis through Sendinblue

With the help of Sendinblue, it is possible for us to analyze our newsletter campaigns. For example, we can see whether a newsletter message was opened and which links, if any, were clicked. In this way, we can determine, among other things, which links have been clicked on particularly often. In addition, we can see whether certain previously defined actions were performed after opening/clicking (conversion rate). We can thus see, for example, whether you have made a purchase after clicking on the newsletter. Sendinblue also allows us to subdivide newsletter recipients based on various categories („clustering“). For example, newsletter recipients can be subdivided according to age, gender or place of residence. In this way, the newsletters can be better adapted to the respective target groups.

If you do not want any analysis by Sendinblue, you must unsubscribe from the newsletter. For this purpose, we provide a corresponding link in every newsletter message. If you want to unsubscribe, you can also do so in your account settings or contact us with your removal request.

For detailed information on the functions of Sendinblue, please refer to the following link: [https://de.sendinblue.com/newsletter-software/](https://de.sendinblue.com/newsletter-software/).

#### Legal Basis

The data is processed on the basis of your consent (Article 6 (1) (a) GDPR). You can revoke this consent at any time. The legality of the data processing that has already taken place remains unaffected by the revocation.

#### Storage time

The data you have stored with us for the purpose of subscribing to the newsletter will be stored by us or the newsletter service provider until you unsubscribe from the newsletter and deleted from the newsletter distribution list after you unsubscribe from the newsletter. Data stored by us for other purposes remains unaffected.

After you have been removed from the newsletter distribution list, your e-mail address may be stored by us or the newsletter service provider in a blacklist if this is necessary to prevent future mailings. The data from the blacklist will only be used for this purpose and will not be merged with other data. This serves both your interest and our interest in complying with the legal requirements when sending newsletters (legitimate interest within the meaning of Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f GDPR). Storage in the blacklist is not limited in time. **You can object to the storage if your interests outweigh our legitimate interests.**

For more information, see Sendinblue's privacy policy at: [https://de.sendinblue.com/datenschutz-uebersicht/](https://de.sendinblue.com/datenschutz-uebersicht/).

#### Order processing

We have concluded an order processing contract (AVV) for the use of the above service. This is a contract required by data protection law, which guarantees that the personal data of our website visitors will only be processed according to our instructions and in compliance with the GDPR.

8\. Plugins and Tools
---------------------

### YouTube with enhanced data protection

This website includes videos from the YouTube website. The site operator is Google Ireland Limited („Google”), Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.

We use YouTube in the extended data protection mode. According to YouTube, this mode means that YouTube does not store any information about visitors to this website before they watch the video. However, the extended data protection mode does not necessarily exclude the transfer of data to YouTube partners. Here's how YouTube - regardless of whether you are watching a video – connect to the Google DoubleClick network.

As soon as you start a YouTube video on this website, a connection to the YouTube servers is established. The YouTube server is informed which of our pages you have visited. If you are logged into your YouTube account, you enable YouTube to assign your surfing behavior directly to your personal profile. You can prevent this by logging out of your YouTube account.

In addition, YouTube can store various cookies on your end device after starting a video or use comparable recognition technologies (e.g. device fingerprinting). In this way, YouTube can receive information about visitors to this website. This information is u.a. used to collect video statistics, improve usability and prevent fraud attempts.

Other data processing operations may be triggered after the start of a YouTube video, over which we have no influence.

YouTube is used in the interest of an attractive presentation of our online offers. This represents a legitimate interest within the meaning of Article 6 Paragraph 1 Letter f GDPR. If a corresponding consent has been requested, the processing takes place exclusively on the basis of Article 6 Paragraph 1 Letter a GDPR and § 25 Para. 1 TTDSG, insofar as the consent includes the storage of cookies or access to information in the user's end device (e.g. device fingerprinting) within the meaning of the TTDSG. Consent can be revoked at any time.

You can find more information about data protection on YouTube in their data protection declaration at: [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de).

### Google reCAPTCHA

We use “Google reCAPTCHA” (hereinafter “reCAPTCHA”) on this website. The provider is Google Ireland Limited (“Google”), Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.

The purpose of reCAPTCHA is to check whether data is entered on this website (e.g. in a contact form) by a human or by an automated program. To do this, reCAPTCHA analyzes the behavior of the website visitor based on various characteristics. This analysis starts automatically as soon as the website visitor enters the website. For the analysis, reCAPTCHA evaluates various information (e.g. IP address, how long the website visitor spends on the website or mouse movements made by the user). The data collected during the analysis will be forwarded to Google.

The reCAPTCHA analyzes run completely in the background. Website visitors are not informed that an analysis is taking place.

The data is stored and analyzed on the basis of Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in protecting its web offers from abusive automated spying and from SPAM. If a corresponding consent has been requested, the processing takes place exclusively on the basis of Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. a GDPR and § 25 Para. 1 TTDSG, insofar as the consent includes the storage of cookies or access to information in the user's end device (e.g. device fingerprinting) within the meaning of the TTDSG. Consent can be revoked at any time.

Weitere Informationen zu Google reCAPTCHA entnehmen Sie den Google-Datenschutzbestimmungen und den Google Nutzungsbedingungen unter folgenden Links: [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de) und [https://policies.google.com/terms?hl=de](https://policies.google.com/terms?hl=de).

### hCaptcha

We use hCaptcha (hereafter “hCaptcha”) on this website. The provider is Intuition Machines, Inc., 2211 Selig Drive, Los Angeles, CA 90026, USA (hereinafter "IMI").

The purpose of hCaptcha is to check whether data entry on this website (e.g. in a contact form) is done by a human or by an automated program. For this purpose, hCaptcha analyzes the behavior of the website visitor based on various characteristics.

This analysis starts automatically as soon as the website visitor enters a website with activated hCaptcha. For the analysis, hCaptcha evaluates various information (e.g. IP address, how long the website visitor spends on the website or mouse movements made by the user). The data collected during the analysis is forwarded to IMI. Is hCaptcha in “invisible mode” is used, the analyzes run completely in the background. Website visitors are not informed that an analysis is taking place.

The data is stored and analyzed on the basis of Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in protecting its web offers from abusive automated spying and from SPAM. If a corresponding consent has been requested, the processing takes place exclusively on the basis of Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. a GDPR and § 25 Para. 1 TTDSG, insofar as the consent includes the storage of cookies or access to information in the user's end device (e.g. device fingerprinting) within the meaning of the TTDSG. Consent can be revoked at any time.

Data processing is based on standard contractual clauses contained in the Data Processing Addendum to the IMI General Terms and Conditions or the Data Processing Agreements.

For more information about hCaptcha, see the privacy policy and terms of use at the following links: [https://www.hcaptcha.com/privacy](https://www.hcaptcha.com/privacy) and [https://hcaptcha.com/terms](https://hcaptcha.com/terms).

### Crisp Chat

In order to improve the user experience in our applications, we use the crisp.chat service provided by Crisp IM SARL, which has its registered office at 149 Rue Pierre Semard, 29200 Brest, France. With the help of crisp.chat, we can offer our users a faster and more direct connection as well as an effective processing of their requests. To achieve this purpose, where permitted by law, we may send users messages via live chat, email, SMS or push messages via crisp.chat. For this we have to synchronize the contact details of the users - e-mail address, link to the avatar picture and username - via an interface with Crisp IM SARL. Crisp IM SARL's privacy policy is available at [https://crisp.chat/en/privacy/](https://crisp.chat/en/privacy/) available. Crisp IM SARL is also compliant with the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). For more information, see [https://help .crisp.chat/en/article/whats-crisp-eu-gdpr-compliance-status-nhv54c](https://help.crisp.chat/en/article/whats-crisp-eu-gdpr-compliance-status-nhv54c).

### Beamer

Beamer: We utilize Beamer to keep our customers informed about essential updates, news, and changes, while also gathering user feedback on our latest developments. Beamer employs cookies and various technologies to gather data related to user behavior and device usage, including but not limited to anonymous IP addresses, device identification, browser details, geographic data (country), preferred language settings, and more. Beamer securely stores this information in a pseudonymous user profile. Neither Beamer nor we will utilize this data for individual user identification or future comparisons. The legal basis for this type of data processing is your consent, Article 6 (1) (a) GDPR. Beamer processes the data on our behalf on the basis of an order processing contract between us and Beamer. This ensures that data processing on our behalf is carried out in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation while guaranteeing the protection of the rights of the data subjects. You can review Beamer's privacy policy at: https://www.getbeamer.com/privacy-policy.

9\. eCommerce and payment processors
------------------------------------

### Processing of customer and contract data

We collect, process and use personal customer and contract data to establish, structure and change our contractual relationships. We collect, process and use personal data about the use of this website (usage data) only insofar as this is necessary to enable the user to use the service or to bill the user. The legal basis for this is Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR.

The collected customer data will be deleted after completion of the order or termination of the business relationship and expiry of any statutory retention periods. Statutory retention periods remain unaffected.

### Data transmission upon conclusion of contract for online shops, dealers and goods dispatch

If you order goods from us, we will pass on your personal data to the transport company responsible for the delivery and to the payment service provider responsible for processing the payment. Only data that the respective service provider needs to fulfill its task will be released. The legal basis for this is Article 6 Paragraph 1 Letter b GDPR, which permits the processing of data to fulfill a contract or pre-contractual measures. If you have given your consent in accordance with Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit of your order; You can withdraw your consent at any time.

If we owe you updates for goods with digital elements or for digital products on the basis of a corresponding contract, we process the contact data you provided when ordering (name, address, e-mail address) in accordance with Art. e-mail address) in order to inform you personally about upcoming updates within the scope of our legal information obligations via a suitable communication channel (e.g. by post or e-mail). Your contact details will be used strictly for the purpose of notifying you of updates we owe you and will only be processed by us to the extent that this is necessary for the information in question.

In order to carry out the payment, the payment data will be transmitted to the relevant payment service provider. The legal basis for this data processing is Art. 6 Para. 1 b GDPR (contractual obligation). The data protection regulations of the respective third-party providers involved in the ordering process apply. 

We use the shop system of the service provider **Bright Market, LLC dba FastSpring ("FastSpring")** for the purpose of hosting and displaying the online shop on the basis of order processing on our behalf. All data collected during the ordering process on this website is processed on FastSpring's servers. As part of FastSpring's aforementioned services, data may also be transmitted to (1) Bright Market, LLC dba FastSpring. 801 Garden St., Santa Barbara, CA 93101, (2) Bright Market LLC dba Fast Spring Limited. 2 Minton Place, Victoria Road, Bicester, England, OX26 6QB, (3) FastSpring B.V. Strawinskylaan 3101 Tenant B.V. 1077 ZX Amsterdam, The Netherlands or (4) SalesRight Technologies ULC d.b.a FastSpring, c/o Volta Labs, Unit 100, 1505 Barrington Street. Halifax, Nova Scotia, B3J 3K5, Canada for further processing. Order processing takes place via FastSpring as the merchant of record for all orders. Your data will be passed on for the purpose of payment and Contract Processing and only to the extent that it is necessary for this. For more information on handling user data, see FastSpring's privacy policy at [https://fastspring.com /legal/](https://fastspring.com/legal/). Please note that FastSpring's privacy policy applies to purchase and we inform and require you to read and accept their privacy policy in order to make the purchase. If you do not provide such consent or consent, you may not be able to enter into a purchase agreement with FastSpring. Before entering the ordering process, no user-assignable data will be transmitted to FastSpring.

### Data transmission when concluding a contract for services and digital content

We only transmit personal data to third parties if this is necessary in the context of Contract Processing, for example to the bank commissioned with payment processing.

There will be no further transmission of the data or only if you have expressly consented to the transmission. Your data will not be passed on to third parties without your express consent, for example for advertising purposes.

The basis for data processing is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit. b GDPR, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a contract or pre-contractual measures.

### Payment Services

We integrate third-party payment services on our website. If you make a purchase from us, your payment details (e.g. name, payment amount, account details, credit card number) will be processed by the payment service provider for the purpose of payment processing. The respective contract and data protection provisions of the respective provider apply to these transactions. The payment service providers are used on the basis of Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR (Contract Processing) and in the interest of a payment process that is as smooth, convenient and secure as possible (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR). Insofar as your consent is requested for certain actions, Article 6 (1) (a) GDPR is the legal basis for data processing; Consent can be revoked at any time for the future.

We use the following payment services / payment service providers on this website:

#### PayPal

The provider of this payment service is PayPal (Europe) S.à.r.l. et Cie, S.C.A., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg (hereinafter "PayPal"). Data transfer to the USA is based on the standard contractual clauses of the EU Commission. Details can be found here: [https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/pocpsa-full](https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/pocpsa-full). Details can be found in PayPal's privacy policy: [https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full](https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full).

#### Apple Pay

The provider of the payment service is Apple Inc., Infinite Loop, Cupertino, CA 95014, USA. You can find Apple's privacy policy at: [https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/de-ww/](https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/de-ww/).

#### Google Pay

Provider is Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland. You can find Google's privacy policy here: [https:// policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

#### Sofortüberweisung

The provider of this payment service is Sofort GmbH, Theresienhöhe 12, 80339 Munich (hereinafter “Sofort GmbH”). With the help of the “Sofort&uum;l;berweisung” we receive a payment confirmation from Sofort GmbH in real time and can start fulfilling our obligations immediately. If you choose the payment method “Sofort ” decided, send the PIN and a valid TAN to Sofort GmbH, which they can use to log into your online banking account. Sofort GmbH automatically checks your account balance after logging in and carries out the transfer to us using the TAN you have transmitted. It then immediately sends us a transaction confirmation. After logging in, your sales, the credit limit of the overdraft facility and the existence of other accounts and their balances are also automatically checked. In addition to the PIN and the TAN, the payment data you enter as well as personal data are transmitted to Sofort GmbH. Your personal data includes first and last name, address, telephone number(s), e-mail address, IP address and any other data required for payment processing. The transmission of this data is necessary to establish your identity beyond doubt and to prevent attempts at fraud. Details on payment with immediate transfer can be found in the following links: [https://www.sofort.de/datenschutz.html](https://www.sofort.de/datenschutz.html) and [https://www.klarna.com/sofort/](https://www.klarna.com/sofort/).

#### Amazon Pay

The provider of this payment service is Amazon Payments Europe S.C.A., 38 avenue J.F. Kennedy, L-1855 Luxembourg. Details on how your data is handled can be found in the Amazon Pay data protection declaration under the following link: [https://pay.amazon.de/help/201212490?ld=APDELPADirect](https://pay.amazon.de/help/201212490?ld=APDELPADirect).

#### giropay

The provider of this payment service is paydirekt GmbH, Stephanstraße 14 - 16, 60313 Frankfurt am Main (hereinafter “giropay”). Details can be found in giropay's data protection declaration: [https://www.paydirekt.de/agb/index.html](https://www.paydirekt.de/agb/index.html).

#### American Express

The provider of this payment service is American Express Europe S.A., Theodor-Heuss-Allee 112, 60486 Frankfurt am Main, Germany (hereinafter “American Express”). American Express may transfer data to its parent company in the United States. Data transfer to the USA is based on the Binding Corporate Rules. Details can be found here: [https://www.americanexpress.com/en-pl/company/legal/privacy-centre/european-implementing-principles/](https://www.americanexpress.com/en-pl/company/legal/privacy-centre/european-implementing-principles/). For more information, see the American Express privacy policy: [https://www.americanexpress.com/de/legal/online-datenschutzerklarung.html](https://www.americanexpress.com/de/legal/online-datenschutzerklarung.html).

#### Mastercard

The provider of this payment service is Mastercard Europe SA, Chaussée de Tervuren 198A, B-1410 Waterloo, Belgium (hereinafter “Mastercard”). Mastercard may transfer data to its parent company in the United States. Data transmission to the USA is based on Mastercard's Binding Corporate Rules. Details can be found here: [https:/ /www.mastercard.de/de-de/datenschutz.html](https://www.mastercard.de/de-de/datenschutz.html) and [https://www.mastercard.us/content/dam/mccom/global/documents/mastercard-bcrs.pdf](https://www.mastercard.us/content/dam/mccom/global/documents/mastercard-bcrs.pdf).

#### VISA

The provider of this payment service is Visa Europe Services Inc., London Branch, 1 Sheldon Square, London W2 6TT, United Kingdom (hereinafter “VISA”). Great Britain is considered a safe third country in terms of data protection. This means that Great Britain has a level of data protection that corresponds to the level of data protection in the European Union. VISA may transfer data to its parent company in the United States. Data transfer to the USA is based on the standard contractual clauses of the EU Commission. Details can be found here: [https://www.visa.de/Terms of Use/visa-globale-datenschutzmitteilung/mitteilung-zu-srechtigkeitsfragen-fur-den-ewr.html](https://www.visa.de/Terms%20of%20Use/visa-globale-datenschutzmitteilung/mitteilung-zu-srechtigkeitsfragen-fur-den-ewr.html).

For more information, see the VISA privacy policy: [https://www.visa.de/bedingungen/visa-privacy-center.html](https://www.visa.de/TERM/visa-privacy-center.html).

#### FastSpring

As described above, the online shop system of the provider FastSpring is integrated into our website. Information on data processing by FastSpring can be found here:[https://fastspring.com/legal/](https://fastspring.com/legal/). You have been informed about the processing of your data through the use of FastSpring during the purchase process through the data protection declaration of FastSpring as the responsible body. Apart from the data provided by FastSpring, we do not collect any further personal data from you during the ordering process, unless otherwise stated here. When you make a purchase from our FastSpring store, FastSpring transfers your personal data to us so that we can perform the contract with you. This data is stored by us and used for the following purposes: to identify the customer, to carry out the contract (in particular shipping, collection if necessary), for correspondence with the customer, if necessary to clarify liability or Warranty claims and the assertion of any claims against customers. The legal basis for processing is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. b GDPR.

### Final Provisions

Users may find content on our website that links to the websites and services of our customers, partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. We have no control over the content or links appearing on those websites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites which are linked to or originate from our website. In addition, these websites or services, including their content and links, may change from time to time. These websites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites that have a link to our site, is subject to that website's own terms and policies.

We have the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. If we do, we will notify you of any such changes and the most current version of this policy.

For users who reside in the state of California, this [Privacy Notice is for California Residents Regarding the CCPA](https://flightsim.to/legal/ccpa) is part of the Privacy Policy. The CCPA gives California residents certain privacy rights with respect to the personal information we collect.

### **Contact**

If you have any questions or comments about this privacy statement, please contact the above data controller at [\[email protected\]](https://flightsim.to/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). To delete your account and associated data, please read [this article](https://flightsim.to/help/user-account/how-can-i-delete-my-account).

Last Updated: November 05, 2022

* [Change consent](javascript:void(0))
* [Change Language](javascript:void())

Partnered with industry-leading companies  

2024 © [Flightsim.to](https://flightsim.to/) | All rights reserved.  
We are not affiliated with Microsoft, Asobo or Flight Simulator in any way.

### Welcome back!

Sign in to your account below or create a free account in just a few seconds.

Login

##### Change Language

Your current language setting is **English**. You are about to change your default language.  

  English Deutsch Nederlands Français Italiano русский Español Dansk Polskie Suomi Português Ελληνικά čeština Română 中文 日本語 български Magyar Svenska
